(
"ai_sub_version": "1.9.2",
"subtitles_prompt_version": 2,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": "gemini-cli:gemini-3-flash-preview",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true
),
"gemini_cli": (
"timeout": 600
)
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": true,
"fps": 1,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"encoder": "libx264"
)
),
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"subtitles": 8
),
"retry": (
"run": 3,
"max": 9,
"delay": 30
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": false,
"scrub": true
)
#不知火フレア生誕祭LIVE
#ShiranuiFlareBirthdayLive
不知火フレア Birthday LIVE 2022
Shiranui Flare Birthday Live 2022
JOINT
作詞 川田まみ 作曲 中沢伴行
Lyrics: Mami Kawada / Composition: Tomoyuki Nakazawa
映し出してみた世界は
The world I saw reflected
塵と残像の淡い影
Faint shadows of dust and afterimages
凛とした背中には
On that dignified back
そのすべてを背負う覚悟がある
Is the resolve to shoulder it all
どうしたいの?
What do you want to do?
そうして
Do it like that
孤独な旅路をそう 決めたはずだったのに
Even though I should have decided on a lonely journey
この手を離さないで
Don't let go of this hand
君から伝わる想いから
From the feelings that come from you
心に眠る願いが目覚める
The wishes sleeping in my heart awaken
強い視線の彼方
Beyond that strong gaze
迷いない二人の姿が見える
I can see the forms of two without hesitation
だから進むの さらなる時へ
So let's move forward, to a further time
砕けてく風景に
In the shattering scenery
生きることの軌跡を知る
I learn the trajectory of living
特別な意味求め
Seeking a special meaning
彷徨い歩く道なき道を
A pathless path walked while wandering
信じたいの
I want to believe
信じて
Believe
ともに行くと そう決めて欲しかったから
Because I wanted you to decide to go together
瞳をそらさないで
Don't look away
うまく言葉にできないけど
I can't put it into words well, but
胸の深く君を求めている
Deep in my heart, I am seeking you
希望の遥か彼方
Far beyond hope
迷いない二人の姿が見える
I can see the forms of two without hesitation
だから進むの 次なる場所へ
So let's move forward, to the next place
悔しさや悲しみが
Regret and sadness
今までそれ以上の喜びを教えてくれた
Taught me joys even greater than those until now
そして隣にいつも
And always by my side
必ず君という存在があるということも
There is always the fact that you exist
感じるでしょ もう何も怖くない
You feel it, right? I'm not afraid of anything anymore
ない！
No way!
この手を握りしめて
Grip this hand tight
君にしか出せない力が
The power only you can produce
夢を現実に変えていくから
Will change dreams into reality
強い視線の彼方
Beyond the strong gaze
迷いない二人の姿が
The figures of the two without hesitation
見える だから進むのさ
Can be seen, so we move forward
さあ鳴るところへ
Now, to where it sounds
はー！はーい！
Haa! Hi!
ということで！
And so!
皆さん、こんぬい！
Everyone, Kon-nui!
ホロライブ3期生の不知火フレアです。
I'm Shiranui Flare from Hololive 3rd Gen.
本日は生誕祭2022、私の誕生日のライブに来てくださり、皆さん本当にありがとうございます。
Thank you all so much for coming to my Birthday Live 2022 today.
本来私の誕生日、4月なんですけど、まぁちょっと色んな自分のスケジュールの兼ね合いとかもありまして、まぁちょっとね遅れまして6月にやらせていただくことになりました。
My birthday is actually in April, but due to various scheduling reasons, I'm holding it a bit late in June.
いや、本当に待ってくれていたエルフレンドたちも本当にね、お待たせしました。ありがとね。
To all the Elfriends who were waiting, sorry to keep you. Thank you.
ま、今日はね、たくさん盛り上がって、もらえたら嬉しいなと思います。
Well, I hope everyone gets really hyped up today.
ゲストもね、たくさんいますのでね、みんなで楽しもう！
There are many guests too, so let's all have fun together!
あれ？なんかでも、ちょっとステージをもうちょっと、なんかもうちょっとない？私っぽい要素なんかもうちょっとないですか？
Huh? But wait, the stage... isn't there something missing? Isn't there something more "me" that we can add?
もっとスタッフ、お！おお！おお！おお！
Help me out, staff! Oh! Whoa! Whoa! Whoa!
え、すごい森！森になって、めっちゃ森。
Whoa, a forest! It's turned into a forest, a total forest.
え、なんかエルフレンドも、もしかしてこれ何？立体？
Eh, and are these Elfriends too? Wait, what are these? 3D?
立体じゃね？え、凄くない？動いてる、ちょっと動いて...え！まばたきして、可愛い。
They're 3D, right? Whoa, isn't that amazing? They're moving... Oh! They blinked, so cute.
え、そんな君たちはEN、JP、オーソドックスなのもいるけど、君たちは何してくれ係？今日。
Well, you guys—there's EN, JP, and the standard ones—what are your roles for today?
何かしてくれるって聞いたけど。
I heard you'd be doing something for me.
え、太鼓？え、可愛い。トントントントントントントン。
Eh, drums? Oh, how cute. Ton-ton-ton-ton...
え、EN、EN君は？
What about EN-kun?
おっほ！可愛い、マラカス！シャンシャンシャンシャンシャンシャンシャン。
Whoa! Cute, maracas! Shan-shan-shan-shan...
え、じゃあ普通のオーソドックス君は？
Then, what about the regular Orthodox-kun?
あ、タンバリン！可愛いね。シャンシャンシャンシャン、シャカシャカシャカシャカ、ドドドドド。
Ah, tambourine! How cute. Shan-shan-shan, shaka-shaka-shaka, do-do-do-do.
ということで、今日はですね、あのエルフレンドたちと一緒に、このライブをゲストと一緒に盛り上げていきますので、みんなもたくさん楽しんでください！
So, today, together with the Elfriends and my guests, we'll be livening up this show, so please enjoy yourselves!
では、いってみましょう！
Now, let's get started!
神様はエレキ守銭奴
作詞・作曲：タカハシヨウ
Kami-sama wa Eleki Shugendo
Lyrics & Music: Takahashi Yo
この度、この太陽系に
This time, in this solar system
新たに惑星を作る神様です。
is the god who creates new planets.
会議で決まった予算は
The budget decided at the meeting
日本円にして千円。
is 1,000 Japanese yen.
潤沢とは到底言えませんが
I can't exactly say it's abundant, but
そこは私の腕の見せどころ
that's where I show off my skills.
神々への節約テクを駆使して
Using the saving techniques of the gods
体裁だけは保って見せましょう。
I'll make sure to at least keep up appearances.
低予算で作った生き物に
The creatures I made on a low budget,
人間と名付けてみました。
I've decided to call them "humans."
誤作動だらけのちんぷな頭
With simple brains full of malfunctions,
足りないパーツは七つ星
and seven missing parts.
彼らはなかなか厄介な
They possess a rather troublesome
不屈の精神力をお持ちで
unyielding strength of spirit.
祈りはフリーダイヤルみたいに掴もう
Let's catch their prayers like a toll-free call.
費用はこっちで負担しているんだから
Since we're the ones covering the costs.
そんなとこにお金がたかると
If money is spent on such things,
オゾン層維持するお金をケチっちゃうぞ
we'll have to skimp on maintaining the ozone layer.
お前らの半熟の未里展開を
Your half-baked future plans
有線LANで繋げてやるから
I'll connect them with a wired LAN.
人間と名付けた生き物は
The creatures named humans
足りない頭で考える
think with their inadequate brains.
…この星の秘密を知りたがる
...wanting to know the secrets of this planet
出汁麺つめただけの地殻
The crust made of only chilled dashi noodles
エアコン切れてただけの氷河期
The ice age caused by a turned-off air conditioner
恐竜の化石は趣味のプラモ
Dinosaur fossils are just hobby plastic models
とか気づかないで
Don't notice that
ブレーカー落ちてる間にマンモス滅んだ
The mammoths went extinct while the breaker was down
これぞ御電化 惑星の理屈
That's electrification—the logic of the planet
金星の神から輸入してた
Imported from the God of Venus
電気代値上がりしたからケチってたんだ
They were being stingy because the electricity bill went up
このペースだとあと数年で
At this rate, in a few years
予算を使い切りそう
the budget will run out
どうやって埋めましょ
How should we fill it?
予算があれば地軸は真っ直ぐにできたし
If we had the budget, the Earth's axis could have been straight
完璧な生き物にもできたんだ でもケチ
And we could have made perfect creatures, but we're stingy
地軸の傾きは四季を産んで
The tilt of the Earth's axis gave birth to the four seasons
不完全な心は愛を産んだ 案外いい星になった
And the imperfect heart gave birth to love—it turned out to be a pretty good planet
でももう無理こんなクソ星捨てるわ
But it's no use, I'm throwing this crappy planet away
そのお金で天国の個室買う
And buying a private room in heaven with that money
あとはせいぜい上手く歩めよ人共
The rest of you humans, try your best to walk well
私なしじゃすぐ死ぬだろうけど
Though you'll probably die soon without me
せっかくだし最後に悠久でも取って
Since I'm at it, I'll take an eternity's worth of leave at the end
温泉に行くことにするかな
And decide to go to an onsen
おたのしみにー！
Enjoy!
はぁー、はぁー。
Haa, haa.
お湯、良かったねー！
The bath was great, wasn't it!
いい湯だったー。いやー、ご飯美味しかったー。
It was a good bath. Man, the food was delicious.
ねえ、最高だったー。ねー。
Yeah, it was the best. Right?
いやー、なんか、ねねちとはさ、なんか、
Man, you know, with Nene-chi, we go out for meals
ご飯とか裏ではね、結構行ったりとか、そう、しているんだけど。
and stuff behind the scenes quite often.
うんうん。
Yeah, yeah.
温泉は初めてだね、じゃなくて。
This is the first time we've been to an onsen... wait, no.
ま、それは置いといて。今日ね、来てくれてどうもありがとうございます。
Well, setting that aside. Thank you so much for coming today.
いや、こちらこそ！ふーたん、お誕生日おめでとう！
No, the pleasure is mine! Fuu-tan, happy birthday!
ありがとうー！
Thank you!
いや、なんかさ、ねねちとはコラボとかは、実は二人で、とかはないんじゃない？
Well, you know, we haven't actually done a collab just the two of us, have we?
おー、確かに確かに。
Oh, you're right, you're right.
そう、なんかゴールデンウィークとかにさ、
Yeah, like during Golden Week, we got all hyped up
一緒になってゲーム盛り上がったりとかね、頑張ったりとか、したけどさ。
playing games together and worked hard and stuff.
ねえ、楽しかったよね。
Yeah, that was fun.
そう、だから二人で何かするっていうの、ずっと実は、やってみたいなって思ってたんだよね。
So, I'd actually been wanting to do something just the two of us for a long time.
えー、何それー！嬉しいんだけどー！ねねちー！
Eh, what's that! I'm so happy! Nene-chi!
嬉しい、嬉しい、嬉しい。
So happy, so happy, so happy.
で、それで、なんかねねちってさ、
And then, I heard that Nene-chi can hit
結構なんか高いのとかも出るってさ、聞いたからさ。
quite high notes too.
歌枠とかもさ、めちゃめちゃ高いのとか出るからさ、
You hit really high notes in your singing streams too,
この歌を、あの、実は、歌いたいと思ってたんだけど。
so I'd actually been wanting to sing this song...
歌えるのもう、ねねちしかいないんじゃないかと思って、ねねちにさ。
I thought Nene-chi might be the only one who could sing it, so I asked her.
めっちゃ合ってるじゃん。ちょっとさ、ねねちとは普通の曲じゃなくて、
It suits you so well. I wanted to sing something a bit interesting
なんかちょっと面白い、かつ、なんか好きな曲、歌いたいなと思ってて。
and a song I like with Nene-chi, rather than just a normal song.
確か、確かに。
True, true.
いや、もうねねちにぴったりじゃんって思ってたんだよね。
Yeah, I thought it was just perfect for Nene-chi.
いや、ねね、この曲、あのふーたんに教えてもらって初めて、あの覚えたんだけど。
Well, I only learned this song for the first time after Fuu-tan told me about it.
いや、本当なんか不思議な曲だし、でも楽しくて。
Yeah, it's really a strange song, but it's fun.
いや、でも高いわ。
But man, it's high.
いや、でもね、本当ありがとう。すごかったよ。
No, but seriously, thank you. You were amazing.
いや、うちら声の相性めっちゃ良くない？
Hey, don't our voices go really well together?
ある、それは本当、また一緒に歌おうよ。
They do, they really do. Let's sing together again.
ねえ、歌いたい歌いたい。
Yeah, I want to, I want to.
ねえ、今めちゃめちゃ疲れてると思うけど、ちょっとめちゃめちゃさ、ちょっと頑張ったから。
Yeah, I bet you're exhausted right now, because we really put in a lot of effort.
いや、本当ありがとう。リハとかも大変だったけどさ。
No, thank you so much. Rehearsals were tough too.
いや、本当、歌だけと言わず、あの、これからも、ゲームもよろしくお願いますよ。
Seriously, not just singing, please keep playing games with me too from now on.
ちょっと、最後に写真撮ろう、写真。
Let's take a photo at the end, a photo.
あ、撮る撮る撮る撮る。
Oh, let's take it, let's take it.
イエーイ！ピース、ハピバハピバ。
Yay! Peace, happy birthday, happy birthday.
ハッピーイエーイ！ありがとう、ありがとう！
Happy yay! Thank you, thank you!
あ、ちょっとまださ、あのーに...
Wait, I still have some...
人間、地球のさ、お金残ってるからさ、
Human, Earth money left, so
余った分で行かない？
why don't we go somewhere with the extra?
あ、行こう、行こう、行こう！
Oh, let's go, let's go, let's go!
別府とか温泉とか海とか！
To Beppu, or a hot spring, or the sea!
いいなー！イエーイ！レッツゴー、レッツゴー、レッツゴー！
That sounds great! Yay! Let's go, let's go, let's go!
Ready or not!
Bring it on!
劣等上等
作詞：Reol 作曲：Giga
Bring It On
Lyrics: Reol Composition: Giga
Hey! Hey! Hey!
劣等上等　不敵に笑って
Bring it on! With a fearless smile.
Hey! Hey! Hey!
劣等上等　不敵に笑って
Bring it on! With a fearless smile.
子供騙しのマセマティカ
Childish mathematics.
露呈したって　そんなんじゃ　プライドがない
Even if exposed, there's no pride in that.
懲りばけーしょん気取りで
Pretending to be on a fixed vacation.
高みの見物ばかりじゃつまんねぇ
It's no fun just watching from above.
ほらもっと　間違って上等
Hey, more mistakes are fine!
退屈に手をかけて
Reach out to the boredom.
ママ、やっぱ私　こんなところじゃ終われない
Mama, as I thought, I can't end in a place like this.
ぬるくて気が触れそう
It's so lukewarm, I'm going crazy.
ごっこ遊びも芝居もさよなら
Goodbye to make-believe and acting.
ずっとこのままなんてさ
Staying like this forever is...
いらないよ
not what I want.
ダッダッダ　あたし大人になる
Da-da-da, I'm going to become an adult.
酸いも甘いも噛み分けて今
Experiencing the bitter and the sweet now.
パッパッパ　変わる時代
Pa-pa-pa, the changing times.
悪いことばかりじゃないでしょう
It's not all bad, is it?
過去も　罪も　罰も　すべて
The past, the sins, the punishments, everything.
素手で　愛で　生き抜いて　覆すわ
With bare hands and love, I'll survive and overturn it.
HA 超 HOT　私たちはNO DOUBT
Ha, super hot, we are no doubt.
緑のあいつにバカ構ってんね
Don't bother with that green guy.
サボ　あいつになったら貰える合格
Skip it, you'll pass if you become that guy.
赤ペン入れてよどこがダメなんですか
Mark it with a red pen, tell me what's wrong.
酒、女、金、じゃやってコンプラ
Alcohol, women, money, that's the compliance.
知るかよ　あーあ
I don't care, ah well.
冗談じゃバカしちゃう
Don't kid me, I'll go crazy.
中指立てたくなるような事情ありすぎて指が足りねぇからハンズアップ
Too many reasons to give the finger, not enough fingers, so hands up.
AND WHAT'S UP　最低？　もともとだろ
And what's up? The worst? I've always been.
BRING IT ON!
ママ、何回だって
Mama, no matter how many times,
欲しがります死ぬまでは
I'll keep wanting until I die.
伸びた背丈　育った街に投げキス
Taller now, a blown kiss to the town where I grew up.
見せ場はこっから
The highlight starts here.
覚悟しとけよ
Be prepared.
ダッダッダ　僕ら大人になる
Da-da-da, we're going to become adults.
数え切れない最低な日々に
In these countless terrible days.
淡々と　かます一撃
A cool, calculated strike.
誰も読めない先まで行こうぜ、ほら
Let's go further than anyone can predict, come on!
過去も　罪も　罰も　すべて
The past, the sins, the punishments, everything.
素手で　愛で　生き抜いて　覆すわ
With bare hands and love, I'll survive and overturn it.
ダッダッダ　くだらない
Da-da-da, it's trivial.
ことばっか譲れない
I won't give in on these things.
わかるか？　私の美学
Do you understand? My aesthetics.
この馬鹿正直な拳ひとつが
This single, brutally honest fist.
一途なんです
It's single-minded.
切り札
My trump card.
愚直なんです
It's straightforward.
ガナるレット
Roaring let...
打ち抜けよ
Shoot through it!
さらば！
Farewell!
こんなもんじゃない！
It's not just this!
ダッダッダ　あたし大人になる
Da-da-da, I'm going to become an adult.
酸いも甘いも噛み分けて今
Experiencing the bitter and the sweet now.
燦々と　交わる未来
A brilliantly intersecting future.
悪いことばかりじゃないでしょう
It's not all bad, is it?
最大級の　馬鹿でいさせて
Let me be the biggest fool.
素手で　攻めて　生き抜いて　上等だわ
Attacking with bare hands and surviving, it's fine by me.
AH...
愛ある時代
An era with love.
Hey! Hey! Hey! Hey!
それでは皆様お先にバイバイ
Well then, everyone, bye-bye for now!
フレアが
Flare has...
湧き上がりましたー！
...warmed up!
ああ、上げた手を下げちゃったよ。
Ah, I finally put down the hand I held up.
上げた手でジャンケンをしちゃったよ。
I ended up playing rock-paper-scissors with my hand held up.
今の最後何だった？
What was that last one you showed?
え、グーだよ。
Uh, it was rock.
あ、じゃあ勝ったわ。
Oh, then I won.
何だよ！うそーん！今パーだったよ！
What?! No way! I showed paper just now!
ジャンケンしてた？
Wait, were we playing rock-paper-scissors?
じゃ、せっかくだからジャンケンしとく？
Well, since we're at it, shall we play?
ツノまき、ツノまき、ツノまき、ツノまき、ツノまき、ツノまき、
Tsunomaki, Tsunomaki, Tsunomaki, Tsunomaki, Tsunomaki, Tsunomaki,
ジャンケンポン！
Rock-paper-scissors, shoot!
あいこでしょ！
A tie! Again!
いや、今日はありがとね、来てくれて。
Anyway, thanks for coming today.
こちらこそ。こんな、お誕生日やん。
Not at all. It's your birthday after all.
そうなんだよ。
That's right.
おめでたー！
Congratulations!
ありがとー！
Thank you!
呼んでくれて嬉しいんじゃ。
I'm so happy you invited me.
わためのライブをしたときにね
When we did Watame's live...
あの、私たち二人で歌うっていうの初めてだったの、そのとき。
that was the first time the two of us sang together.
そうだね。
That's right.
そこで歌ったのがすごい良かったなと思って、相性めっちゃええやんと思って。
Singing there felt so good, I thought we had amazing chemistry.
それでまた歌いたいなと思って。
It made me want to sing with you again.
ねえ。
Yeah.
やる、そのときもね、この曲も、まあ候補に挙がって。
Actually, even back then, this song was a candidate.
そうそうそうそうそう。
Yes, exactly!
ねえ。
Right.
なんか今回、あの、わために声掛けさせてもらうときに
So this time, when I reached out to Watame...
いや、どうしてもこの曲、やっぱ候補からちょっと外せないやと思って。
I felt like I really couldn't leave this song out.
で、「これ、ちょっとやってみませんか？」って。
So I asked, "Would you like to try this one?"
「やってみましょうよ！」って。
"Let's do it!"
そう、わためがね、「やろう！」って言ってくれて。
Yeah, Watame said, "Let's do it!"
いや、でもめっちゃ良かったよね。
But it was really great, wasn't it?
めっちゃ良かったよね。めっちゃ高かったけどね。
It was really great. It was very high-pitched, though.
あ、それな。
Ah, tell me about it.
ごめんな。
Sorry about that.
でも最後とかさ、元気トークと奥下って感じで、マッチしてたと思わんか？
But at the end, Genki-talk and Okushita felt like they matched perfectly, don't you think?
思わんか？
Don't you think so?
みんなも思わんかー！？
Everyone, don't you think so too!?
最後みんなと一緒にさ、撮って終わろう。
Let's finish by taking a photo with everyone.
オッケー。
Okay.
イエーイ！イエーイ！イエーイ！
Yay! Yay! Yay!
ナイトフィーバー！
Night Fever!
フゥー！
Woo!
はい、ということでね、今日ありがとうございました。
Alright, thank you so much for today.
ありがとうございました。
Thank you so much.
また呼ぶからね。
I'll call you again.
私も呼ぶ。またコラボもしようね。
I'll call you too. Let's collab again.
しようしよう。ありがとね。
Let's do it. Thank you.
ありがとね！バイバイ！
Thank you! Bye-bye!
撃ち抜け バンバンバン
Shoot them down, bang bang bang!
待て、生きるか死ぬか
Wait, it's life or death.
突き詰めりゃそれだけ
That's all it boils down to.
あとはどうにかなっちゃうもんだって
The rest will sort itself out somehow.
確かに、ほうほう
True, I see.
よく聞け、ここじゃ泣き言はいらねえぜ
Listen up, no whining allowed here.
愛情、同情、断捨離の末、感情で
Love, sympathy, after discarding it all, go with emotion.
Wow oh, wow oh, dive into the crazy!
だいぶいい感じ、体に叩き込め
Feeling pretty good, hammer it into your body.
Wow oh, wow oh, inside into the crazy!
なまけるのは百万年早え、はい！
You're a million years too early to slack off, yes!
いつでもそう、いつでもそう立ち塞がるのは
It's always the case, what always stands in your way...
覚えておけ、弱い自分だって
remember this, is your own weak self.
つまりライフ・フル・イチョウ、掃除してネガティブ
In short, life full of choices, sweep away the negative.
決定的に、撃ち抜け
Decisively, shoot them down.
もっとそっと譲れないハートで
With a heart that won't yield, even more softly.
引き金、引きまくれ
Keep pulling that trigger.
言わば完全無双、覚悟ならバッチリで
In a manner of speaking, completely peerless, perfectly prepared.
Wow oh yeah, 逃がさねえ、錆びた価値観
Wow oh yeah, I won't let them escape, those rusted values.
官能が唸る、すぐに排除せよ
Sensuality roars, eliminate them at once.
天上天下、我ら独尊！
Above and below heaven, we alone are honored!
右向け左、よいしょ！
Face right, turn left, yo-ho!
左向け左、そう、よいしょ！
Face left, turn left, yes, yo-ho!
そのまま進め、よいしょ！
Keep moving forward, yo-ho!
全体、止まれ！
Company, halt!
情報戦・追撃戦・上陸戦・籠城戦、基本だって
Info war, pursuit, landing, siege; they're all basics.
なるほど、ふんふん
I see, uh-huh.
必要な素質、それは最上級のIQ
The necessary quality is top-tier IQ.
快楽潜入、監視体制も抜かりねえ
Pleasurable infiltration, surveillance is flawless.
Wow oh, wow oh, dive into the crazy!
だいぶいい感じ、真実を炙り出せ
Feeling pretty good, smoke out the truth.
Wow oh, wow oh, inside into the crazy!
躍らされるな、躍らせてやってよ
Don't be danced around, do the dancing yourself.
いつでもそう、いつでもそう単純なことは
It's always the case, what's always simple...
明かされない、しかしそれが証拠
remains unrevealed, but that in itself is proof.
常にインテリジェンス、磨いて世界を決定的に欺け
Always hone your intelligence and deceive the world for good.
もししどろもどろ攪乱、ここで神様
If you're confused and in disarray, here god...
Ah, 奪ってみるくらい...
Ah, I'll even try to snatch it away...
白兵戦・追撃戦・上陸戦・籠城戦 (Oh yeah!)
Melee, pursuit, landing, siege (Oh yeah!)
情報戦・掃討戦・経済戦・サイバー戦 (Oh yeah!)
Info war, cleanup, economic war, cyber war (Oh yeah!)
白兵戦・追撃戦・上陸戦・籠城戦 (Oh yeah!)
Melee, pursuit, landing, siege (Oh yeah!)
情報戦・掃討戦・経済戦・サイバー戦 (Oh yeah!)
Info war, cleanup, economic war, cyber war (Oh yeah!)
つまりライフ・フル・イチョウ、掃除してネガティブ
In short, life full of choices, sweep away the negative.
決定的に、撃ち抜け
Decisively, shoot them down.
もっとそっと譲れないハートで
With a heart that won't yield, even more softly.
引き金、引きまくれ
Keep pulling that trigger.
言わば完全無双、覚悟ならバッチリで
In a manner of speaking, completely peerless, perfectly prepared.
Wow oh yeah, 逃がさねえ、錆びた価値観
Wow oh yeah, I won't let them escape, those rusted values.
官能が唸る、すぐに排除、排除、排除、排除せよ
Sensuality roars, eliminate them at once, eliminate them!
喝采を修得せよ、盾をその手に
Acquire the applause, shield in your hand.
圧倒的な勝利を
Take overwhelming victory.
もししどろもどろ攪乱、ここで神様
If you're confused and in disarray, here god...
奪ってみるくらい
I'll even try to snatch it away.
言わば完全無欠、上機嫌になるまで
In a manner of speaking, completely flawless, until you're in high spirits.
徹底的に顔を鍛えよう
Let's train your expression thoroughly.
己を無力化して無に仕立て変え
Neutralize yourself and tailor yourself into nothingness.
先端、開け、響け、銃声
Open up the front, let the gunshots ring out.
天上天下、我ら独尊！
Above and below heaven, we alone are honored!
ふぅ～！
Phew!
はぁ... 生き返った～！
Phew... I feel alive again!
フレア先輩！
Flare-senpai!
いやぁ、今日は来てくれてありがとう！
Man, thank you so much for coming today!
いや、こちらこそ！お誕生日おめでとうございます！
No, thank YOU! And happy birthday to you!
ありがとう～！
Thank you!
いや、なんかさ、かなたんとさ、あの、結構今年とか、
You know, Kanatan, we've had quite a few collabs...
去年の終わりぐらいから結構ね、コラボとかさせていただいたりとかね、
...since the end of last year or the start of this year.
非常にね、ちょっと仲良くなってきたなと思って。
I feel like we've become really close.
うん！めっちゃ、ね。結構話す機会が裏でもすごい増えた。
Yeah! Definitely. We've had a lot more chances to talk off-stream too.
そうなの。で、なんか歌とかも歌いたいなと思って、
Exactly. So I really wanted to sing something with you.
そう、この曲とかも、かっこいいところ、
For this song, I thought that part...
あの白兵格劇戦追撃戦のとことか、あそこ絶対かなたんに歌ってもらったら、かっこいいなと思って。
...the "close-quarters combat" part, would sound so cool if you sang it, Kanatan.
いや、もう... めっちゃソロパート偏ってる！
Gosh... That solo part was so intense!
いや、そんな、いいのかな、こんな、いっぱい歌ってと思ったんですけども、めちゃめちゃかっこよかった！
I wondered if it was okay to give you so many lines, but you were amazing!
最初練習したとき、マジで言えなくて。めっちゃ練習しました。本当に。
When I first practiced it, I couldn't say the words at all. I practiced so hard!
いや、本当にありがとう！
Thank you so much, really!
こちらこそね、誘っていただいて、本当に嬉しかったです。ありがとうございました！
No, thank you for inviting me. I was so happy. Thank you very much!
ありがとう！次は、あの「カナリア」で歌いたいね。
Thank you! Next time, I want to sing "Canaria".
ね！ちょっとこよりを、この真ん中に...
Right! We should put Koyori right in the middle...
こより呼ばなきゃ！
We have to invite Koyori!
呼んで「カナリア」でも歌いましょうね。
Let's invite her and sing "Canaria" together.
ね！え、ちょっとさ、記念撮影もしようよ。
Yeah! Hey, let's take a commemorative photo.
したい、したい、したい！撮って撮って！
I want to! Let's do it! Take the picture!
エルフレも一緒にちょっと入れて、エルフレとへいみんと入れて、撮ろう！
Let's get the Elfriends and Heimin in the shot too. Let's take it!
そうだ、そうだ。みんな。
That's a great idea. Everyone!
イェーイ！
Yay!
ここにね、次は「カナリア」で、こよりも入れような！
Next time, we'll have Koyori here for "Canaria" too!
イェーイ！イマジナリーこよりで。イェーイ！
Yay! With an imaginary Koyori. Yay!
いないけど、今、な、ここに入るからな！
She's not here now, but she'll be right here!
はい！ということでね、かなたん、本当にありがとう！今度あの、またコラボも一緒にしようね。
Alright! Kanatan, thank you so much! Let's collab again soon.
ってか、焼肉行かなきゃ！
Actually, we have to go get yakiniku!
焼肉行きましょう！まず。
Let's go get yakiniku! First thing.
まだ行けてないから。あのおごっていただくの楽しみにしてるんで。
We haven't gone yet. I'm looking forward to you treating me!
あ、おごらせていただきます。
Oh, it'll be my treat.
よろしくお願いします！
Looking forward to it!
あ、ありがとう！本当におめでとうございます！ありがとうございました～！
Thank you! Happy birthday again! Thank you so much!
ありがとう～～！
Thank you!
あ、キスされた！
Oh, she kissed me!
好き。
Love ya.
Over The Rainbow
涙の向こうに 架かる虹を
Beyond the tears, a rainbow spans...
いつかは超えてゆける 信じて my friend
Someday I'll cross it, I believe, my friend.
時は 止めどなく寄せる
Time is like waves that roll in...
波のようだな
...without ever stopping.
泳ぎ疲れ いつしか
I was tired from swimming, and before I knew it...
流されそうになっていたよ
...I was about to be swept away.
空は あれから幾つも
Since then, the sky has carried...
季節運んで
...so many seasons past.
君の声を こんなに
To think that your voice...
小さく変えていたなんて
...had been changed to such a small whisper.
何かを掴んだ 指の隙間
Through the gaps in the fingers that grasped something...
キラキラ輝いて 零れたものはなに
...what was it that sparkled and spilled away?
うまくできるほど 苦しくなる
The better I can do it, the more painful it becomes.
誰よりも君はほら 気づいている
More than anyone else, look, you've noticed it.
気づいている
You've noticed it.
そして いつでも平気な
And every time you put on...
顔をするたび
...a face that says everything is okay...
塞ぐ耳で きしんだ 痛みを
...the pain that creaked in my blocked ears...
耳を貸してたんだ 僕も
I was listening too
涙で滲んだ
Blurred by tears
ビルの上に
Above the buildings
見上げる憧れは 確かにここにある
The longing I look up to is surely right here
あの日の胸に
In my heart that day
かけた虹を
The rainbow I cast
追いかけ走り出そう
Let's start running after it
笑って My Friend
Smile, my friend
長い雨が 止むその時
When the long rain stops
冷えすぎたこの頬に
On these chilled cheeks
光をください
Please give me light
迷わずもう二度と
Without hesitation, I'll never
離さないよ
let go of you again
涙で滲んだ
Blurred by tears
ビルの上に
Above the buildings
見上げる憧れは 確かにここにある
The longing I look up to is surely right here
あの日の胸に
In my heart that day
かけた虹を
The rainbow I cast
追いかけ走り出そう
Let's start running after it
笑って My Friend
Smile, my friend
かすかでいいんだ 明日の風に
Even a faint one is fine, in tomorrow's wind
吹かれて僕たちは
Blown by it, we
生きてゆけるはずさ
should be able to live on
涙の向こうに
Beyond the tears
架かる虹を
the rainbow hanging
いつかは越えてゆこう
Someday let's cross it
信じて My Friend
Believe, my friend
笑って My Friend
Smile, my friend
はい！
Yes!
PUPPY LOVE!!
ドッキュン！
Badump!
せーの！ パピーラブ パパパピーラブ
Ready, set! Puppy love, pa-pa-puppy love
第一印象はマジ最悪
First impression was really the worst
パピーラブ パパパピーラブ
Puppy love, pa-pa-puppy love
友達以下ってゆーか天敵
Less than a friend, more like a natural enemy
パピーラブ パパパピーラブ
Puppy love, pa-pa-puppy love
会った途端に
The moment we met
チリチリ
it was sizzle-sizzle
勝手な大人 なにさま？
Selfish adult, who do you think you are?
一番苦手なタイプ
My least favorite type
ほんとあり得ないのね
Really unbelievable, right?
会うたびいつも口喧嘩
Every time we meet, we're always bickering
パピーラブ パパパピーラブ
Puppy love, pa-pa-puppy love
犬と猿 ハブとマングース
Like cats and dogs, like cobras and mongooses
パピーラブ パパパピーラブ
Puppy love, pa-pa-puppy love
急に沈黙
Sudden silence
な、な、なに、この空気？
W-w-what's this atmosphere?
まさか君の顔が赤くなる
No way, your face is turning red
まぶしすぎちゃってどしたの？ パピーラブ
It's too dazzling, what's wrong? Puppy love
わけわかんない わけわかんないで
I don't get it, I don't get it
告白するなんて
Confessing like that...
突然すぎるよ
It's way too sudden!
なぜ？ どうして？
Why? How?
私の胸 破裂しそうなの
My chest feels like it's going to burst
もしかして私も好きなのかな
Could it be that I like you too?
いやいやそんなの絶対ないし
No, no, there's absolutely no way!
キョロキョロ キョロキョロ 超緊張
Looking around, looking around, super nervous
初登場 笑わないで パピーラブ
First appearance, don't laugh, Puppy love
ちょっと待ってよ いきなりすぎない？
Wait a minute, isn't this too sudden?
心の準備もへったくれもない
No time for mental preparation or anything
だいたいなんでこんなわけわかんなくなるの
Why is it becoming so confusing anyway?
全然返事ハイテンパった
I completely panicked with the reply
恋愛対象っていうか友達
More like a friend than a romantic interest
友達っていうか天敵だよね
More like a natural enemy than a friend, right?
会うたびいつも喧嘩 喧嘩
Every time we meet, we're always fighting, fighting
まあ楽しいんだけどさ
Well, it's fun though...
でもあの人は何かが違う
But that person is somehow different
妙にリラックスできるっていうか
I can relax strangely, or something...
でもでも好きとかそういうんじゃなくて
But, but, it's not like I like them or anything...
なんかわかんない気になってるかも
I don't know why, but I might be interested
いやいやいや絶対ないし
No, no, no, there's absolutely no way!
なんでこんなに必死になってるの？
Why am I becoming so desperate?
好き？ 嫌い？ 嫌い？ 好き？ わかんない
Like? Hate? Hate? Like? I don't know!
はい！
Yes!
ドッキュン！
Badump!
せーの！ パピーラブ パパパピーラブ
Ready, set! Puppy love, pa-pa-puppy love
初恋の相手は決めていたんだ
I had already decided on my first love
パピーラブ パパパピーラブ
Puppy love, pa-pa-puppy love
モデルか俳優か王子様
A model, or an actor, or a prince
パピーラブ パパパピーラブ
Puppy love, pa-pa-puppy love
けどどうして？
But why?
わからない
I don't know
君のことだんだん
About you, gradually
好きなのかもって感じる
I feel like I might like you
びっくりしちゃってどしたの？ パピーラブ
It's surprising, what's wrong? Puppy love
わけわかんない わけわかんないで
I don't get it, I don't get it
告白するなんて
Confessing like that...
突然すぎるよ
It's way too sudden!
...パピラ
...Papira.
わけわかんない わけわかんない
I don't understand, I don't understand.
もちろん 自分のこの気持ち
Of course, these feelings of mine
理解不能だよ
are beyond comprehension.
こいしちゃ こいしちゃ こいしちゃ
Falling in love, falling in love, falling in love.
やっぱり やっぱり 変かしら
Is it really, really strange?
ねぇ 誰か教えて
Hey, someone tell me.
55万 回答 なんか教科書 どこにも載ってないし
550,000 answers, but it's not in any textbook,
こんな気持ちは初めてだから
because these feelings are a first for me.
ああ そういえばいつか
Ah, come to think of it, someday
凹んだとき
when I was feeling down,
大丈夫 大丈夫
it's okay, it's okay,
なんとかなるよって
you said it'll work out somehow,
手を握ってくれた
and held my hand.
わけわかんない わけわかんない
I don't understand, I don't understand.
ねぇ 告白するなんて
Hey, to confess my love
突然すぎだよ
is too sudden.
なぜ どうして 私の胸
Why, oh why, is my heart
破裂しそうなの
about to burst?
なぜか 私も好きと言ったの おかしいかな
I wonder if it's weird that I said I like you too.
メガキャラ キャラ キャダ キャダ キャダ
Megachara chara kyada kyada kyada!
チョキンチョ ハツドジョ
Chokincho hatsudojo!
わらわらいて パピラ
Warawaraite Papira!
チョキンチョ ハツドジョ
Chokincho hatsudojo!
パピ パピ パピ パピ パピラ
Papi papi papi papi Papira!
（笑い声と歓声）
(Laughter and cheering)
ありがとうー！
Thank you!
最後の最後で！
At the very end!
近かったね、近すぎた！
We were close, too close!
支え合っちゃったけど！
We ended up supporting each other!
支え合っちゃったけど、でも、これフレアが支えてもらえるかもと思ったけど
We did, though I thought maybe I'd be the one Flare would support...
今日何テイク目かわかんないんですけど
I don't know how many takes we've done today...
もういいじゃんいいじゃん！
Oh well, it's fine, it's fine!
いや、それよりもフレア、お誕生日おめぺこー！
Anyway, more importantly, Flare, happy birthday-peko!
ありがとうございます、本当に。
Thank you so much, really.
一緒に歌えてすごい嬉しかったぺこですよ、二人ってなかなかないぺこね。
I was so happy we could sing together-peko. We don't get to do duos very often-peko.
そうなんだよね、今回本当初めて…
That's true. This time was really the first...
ってか、この衣装で、一緒にちゃんと歌うの初めてじゃない？
Wait, isn't this the first time we've actually sung together in these outfits?
しかもさ、ぺこらとフレアの衣装、なんかシナジーあるぺよね。
And besides, Pekora's and Flare's outfits have a kind of synergy-peko.
そうなんだよね、青と白って感じでね。
Right? With the blue and white.
いい感じぺこじゃん！
It looks great-peko!
ぴょんぴょんぴょん！
Pyon pyon pyon!
激しすぎてさ、全然間奏中に喋る余裕なかったんだけど。
It was so intense, I didn't have any room to talk during the instrumental breaks at all.
動きがね。
The movements, yeah.
反対側もちょっとみんなと一緒にさ。
Let's go to the other side with everyone too.
動きに集中しすぎて声がなんか出せなかった。
I focused so much on moving that my voice didn't really come out.
イエーイ！
Yay!
ヤッホー！
Yaho!
本当に来てくれてありがとう。
Thank you so much for coming.
ありがとぺこ！
Thanks-peko!
一緒に歌いたかったんだけど、由香里さんの曲をぺこらと一緒に歌ったら絶対可愛いんじゃないかって思ってたの。
I really wanted to sing together, and I thought if I sang Yukari-san's song with Pekora, it would definitely be cute.
本当ぺこですか？すごい可愛いってぺこですね、これね。
Really-peko? It's super cute-peko, isn't it?
一緒に歌えてよかった。
I'm glad we could sing together.
こちらこそありがとうぺこだよ。まだまだあるもんね。
Thank you too-peko. There's still more to come, right?
そうなんだよ、まだまだコラボとかもあったり、私の曲とかもあったりするので。
That's right. There are still more collaborations and some of my songs too.
頑張ってぺこな、ぺこら見守ってるからね。
Do your best-peko, Pekora will be watching.
ありがとね、ぺこちゃん。
Thanks, Peko-chan.
頑張ってね、フレア！またね！
Good luck, Flare! See ya!
またね！バイバイ！
See ya! Bye bye!
ぺこちゃんと歌えて、素敵な誕生日を迎えられたな。まだまだ続くんですけどね。
Singing with Peko-chan made this a wonderful birthday. But it's not over yet.
次は誰が来てくれるんでしょうか。
I wonder who's coming next.
行くぞ！
Here we go!
おかわり
作詞・作曲：渡辺翔
Okawari
Lyrics/Composition: Sho Watanabe
どんなに どんなに 手を取り合っていても
No matter how much, no matter how much we hold hands,
最後から 最後まで 始まりはない
from the very beginning to the very end, there is no start.
繊細で 臆病な やわらかな心
A delicate, cowardly, soft heart,
崩さないよう 守ろう
let's protect it so it doesn't crumble.
希望の中で 迷子の欠片
A fragment of a lost child amidst hope,
もう あの日と 違っても
even if it's different from that day now,
受け入れるよ
I'll accept it.
どうして 欲しくて あげたくなくて
Why do I want it, yet don't want to give it away?
いつだって いつだって 優しくなれない
I can never, ever be kind.
繰り返して 向き合った
Over and over again, I faced
嘘つきな世界
this lying world.
怖がってた 今までの…
What I've been afraid of until now...
...後悔
...regret
私と消えて
Vanish with me
本当なんて無くたって
Even if there's no such thing as truth
笑おう
Let's laugh
弱くない 弱くない 君は弱くないよ
You're not weak, you're not weak, you aren't weak at all
もらってばかりの私じゃないから
Because I'm not just someone who only receives
最初から最後まで何もなかったなんて
That there was nothing from beginning to end...
言わせないよ絶対
...I'll never let anyone say that
これが物語だったら君を
If this were a story,
この勇気だけでたやすく救えるのに
I could easily save you with just this courage
いつかは追い抜いて
Someday I'll overtake you
振り向いて止まって
Turn around and stop
何回も何回も
Time and time again
名前叫んで自慢げに言おう
I'll shout your name and say it proudly
傷ついて今を見れなくて
Wounded and unable to see the present
夢の中閉じこもり
Shutting myself away in a dream
眠る
I sleep
私に向けて
Turn towards me
信じ合って出会って
Believing in each other and meeting
笑おう
Let's laugh
あやめ先輩!
Ayame-senpai!
あー! ふーちゃん!
Ah! Fu-chan!
うわー!
Uwaa!
いえーい!
Yei!
嬉しい!
I'm so happy!
うわー!
Uwaa!
来てくれてありがとうございます!
Thank you so much for coming!
いえいえ! 誘っていただいてありがとうございます!
No, no! Thank you for inviting me!
こちらこそですよ!
The pleasure is all mine!
ねえ、呼んでいただけて、お邪魔させていただきました!
I'm so glad you called me over to join you!
いえ、ありがとうございまーす!
No, thank YOU!
いえーい!
Yei!
あ、桜が降ってますよ!
Oh, cherry blossoms are falling!
そうなんですよ、あやめ先輩のために用意しました!
That's right, I prepared them just for you, Ayame-senpai!
わあー! やったー!
Waa! Yay!
嬉しい!
I'm so happy!
かわいい、きれいでしょ!
It's cute and beautiful, right?
桜取れないかな、これ。
I wonder if I can catch a petal.
あ、かわいい。
Ah, cute.
そう、あやめ先輩と、あの1月にかなたんの別荘の時に、
Yeah, so, Ayame-senpai and I, back in January at Kanatan's villa...
初めて、お話しさせていただいて。
...we talked for the first time.
そうだよね。
That's right.
「あ、これ友達になれるわ」と思って、もう友達になったつもりでいたんですけど。
I thought, "Oh, we can be friends," and I felt like we were already friends.
いや、つもりじゃないですよ! 友達ですよ!
No, it wasn't just a feeling! We ARE friends!
なんか半年間、何かありましたっけ?
Has it really been half a year since then?
いや、なんかちょっと勘違いしてました私。
No, I guess I was just a bit confused.
いやいやいや、違う違う違う! 違うんですよ!
No, no, no, you've got it all wrong! That's not it!
でも、でも、ちょっとあやめ先輩と思い切って、
But, but, I really wanted to take the leap with Ayame-senpai...
あの、何かしたいなと思ってて。
...and do something together.
一番はやっぱり歌ってみたかったんですよね。
And most of all, I really wanted to try singing with you.
え、でもね、余もね、歌いたかったの、フレアちゃんと!
Eh, but you know, I wanted to sing with you too, Flare-chan!
めっちゃ嬉しいです! めっちゃ合ってません?
I'm so happy! Don't you think our voices matched perfectly?
え、すごい。え、なんかね、余、感動しちゃったの!
Yeah, it was amazing. I was actually quite moved!
いやー! 褒め上手!
Oh, stop it! You're such a flatterer!
いやいや、歌いながら「え、ちょっと余たち良くない?」って思ったし。
No, really, while singing I thought, "Wait, aren't we sounding pretty good?"
私はあやめ先輩ってほんまにかわいいよねって思って。
And I was just thinking about how truly cute you are, Ayame-senpai.
ねえ、ちょっと褒め上手なんですけど!
Hey, look who's the flatterer now!
でもね、なんかもおね、否定できることが何もない。本当にかわいい!
But seriously, there's absolutely nothing I can find fault with. You're just so cute!
ねえ、やだー、えへへ、えへへへ。
Oh, stop it, you're embarrassing me! Ehehe.
もう好き!
I just love you!
じゃあちょっと今日、記念撮影も撮っていいですか?
So, can we take a commemorative photo today too?
え、ぜひお願いします!
Oh, absolutely! Please!
え、ちょっと可愛く撮ってもらってもいいですか?
Could you make sure we look cute in it?
鬼! あ、鬼!
Oni! Ah, Oni!
あ、鬼!
Ah, Oni!
あ、鬼! 鬼! 鬼!
Ah, Oni! Oni! Oni!
かわいい!
So cute!
鬼!
Oni!
にー！おにー！
Ni! Oni!
（笑い声）
(Laughter)
Yeah！ありがとうございます！
Yeah! Thank you so much!
ええ！ありがとうございます！
Yes! Thank you so much!
またあの、今度はあの、何かゲームとか一緒に。
Also, next time, let's play some games together.
うん！ぜひお願いします！
Yeah! I'd love to!
やった！あと雑談もさせてもらいます！
Hooray! And let's do a chatting stream too!
いや、やった！待ってます！
Yay! I'll be waiting!
ありがとうございます！またお願いします！
Thank you! Let's do it again!
はい！ありがとうねー！
Yes! Thank you!
愛してるぞ、百鬼！
I love you, Nakiri!
うーー！
Uuuu!
FPの展開！展開！
FP deployment! Deployment!
いつもこの場所で
作詞・作曲　志倉千代丸
Always in this place
Lyrics/Composition: Chiyomaru Shikura
いつか僕らが未来振り返る時には
Someday, when we look back at the future
いつもこの場所で君が笑って
You'll always be smiling in this place
残酷に過ぎゆく時の中で
Amidst the cruelly passing time
探し求めていたもの
The things I've been searching for
すれ違う世界に閉じ込められた
Locked away in a passing world
目に見えぬ光
An invisible light
特別なほど愛するものへ
To the one I love so much it's special
打ち明けられずにいた
That I haven't been able to open up to
過ごした日々の一つ一つが
Each and every day we spent together
戸惑いを響に変える
Changes confusion into resonance
いつか僕らが未来振り返る時には
Someday, when we look back at the future
いつもこの場所で君が笑って
You'll always be smiling in this place
重ね合ったみんなの思いが
Everyone's overlapping feelings
世界線を作る
Will create a world line
どんな雨にも負けぬ信じ合える気持ち
A feeling of mutual trust that won't give in to any rain
この空の観測者
The observer of this sky
この空は明日の証明
This sky is the proof of tomorrow
いつまでも変わらぬ景色なんて
A scenery that never changes
絶対に叶わぬ夢
Is a dream that will never come true
奇跡のような出会い　せめてあの日を
A miracle-like encounter, at least that day
消したりしないで
Please don't let it disappear
好きな気持ちが勇気に変わる
My feelings of love turn into courage
科学的じゃないけど
It's not scientific, but...
戸惑いのない君の言葉が
Your words, without hesitation
本当の答えを導く
Guide me to the true answer
あの僕らが出会い大切な何かを
On that day we met, something precious
いつもこの場所で探していたね
We were always searching for it in this place
何気なく過ぎゆく時間の
The meaning of the time
その意味を知ってる
That passes by casually, I know it
たとえどんなに二人離れてしまっても
No matter how far apart we become
いつもこの場所で繋がっている
We'll always be connected in this place
切なくてロマンティックだね
It's painful and romantic, isn't it?
まだ知らぬ明日
A tomorrow we don't yet know
いつか僕らが未来振り返る時には
Someday, when we look back at the future
いつもこの場所で君が笑って
You'll always be smiling in this place
重ね合ったみんなの思いが
Everyone's overlapping feelings...
世界征服 どんな雨にも負けぬ信じ合える気持ち
World domination. A feeling of mutual trust that won't give in to any rain.
この空の観測者
This sky's observer.
この空は明日の証明
This sky is the proof of tomorrow.
イエーイ！
Yay!
ラミィ！
Lamy!
いいのかなこれで。
Is this okay?
今のすごいいつMC入る？みたいな顔してたよ。
You had this "When do we start the MC?" look just now.
ちょっと伺っちゃった。
I was a bit hesitant.
いや、まず、お誕生日！
Well, first of all, your birthday!
おめでとう！
Happy Birthday!
ありがとう！おめでとうって言われる前に、ありがとう！
Thank you! Before you even said it, thank you!
気が早い、気が早い。
You're too quick, too quick.
いやなんか、ラミィとはさ、一緒にARKもしてたじゃん。
Well, you know, I played ARK with you, Lamy.
なんかちょっとダサい名前つけてたよね。
You gave it a bit of a tacky name, didn't you?
忘れちゃった、なんだっけ。次のライブまでに思い出しておこうか。
I forgot, what was it? Let's try to remember by the next live.
あの、ARKの時のやつの。
That thing from the ARK days.
なんかダサすぎて忘れちゃった。
It was so tacky I forgot.
でも、今後それでやるんでしょ。
But you're going with that from now on, right?
雪透をやめたんだっけ？
Did we stop being "Yukitoru"?
やめたんだよ。
We did.
ま、今日は、そんな二人で、
Well today, the two of us...
シトさんの曲をね。
will sing a song by Shito.
ラミィにめっちゃ合いそうって思ったから。
I thought it would suit Lamy perfectly.
ミスター・ゲイザー選んできたんだよ。
So I chose "Mister Gazer".
Wikipediaで見た。
I saw it on Wikipedia.
本人に聞きなよ！
Ask me directly!
なんでWikiなんだよ！
Why Wikipedia?!
なんか、調べて、これお前のこと知ってるんやでってアピールしたかった。
I researched it, and I wanted to show that I know about you.
ありがとう、嬉しいよ。
Thank you, I'm happy.
ほら、でも、着替えさせてもらって。
But look, I have to go change now.
イエーイ！
Yay!
そんなテンションなのこれ？
Is that the energy level for this?
イエーイ！
Yay!
なんでだよ、気が合わなすぎるんだけど。
Why?! We're so out of sync.
いや、ありがとう、じゃあまた一緒に。また、また一緒に。
Well, thank you. Let's do this again. See you soon.
ありがとうね！
Thank you!
んーまっ！
*Blows kiss*
ハウトゥー世界征服 作詞・作曲：Neru
How-to World Domination / Lyrics & Composition: Neru
泣きべそ隠してんのは どちら様
Who's the one hiding their tears?
笑われた分だけやり返せ
Pay them back for every time they laughed at you.
今に見てろと 手に取ったものは
"Just you wait," I said as I picked up...
爆弾やナイフなんてもんじゃないけど
though it wasn't something like a bomb or a knife.
一切合切今後どうなったって約束しよう
No matter what happens from here on out, let's promise
背中の値札を引き剥がせ
to rip off the price tag on our backs.
廃材みたいな毎日だけど
Our days might feel like scrap material, but
捨てるのはまだ早いだろ
it's too early to throw them away.
今日も ぼっち丸めながら
Today again, curling up alone
終点駅のホームで
on the platform of the terminal station.
明日の僕をまだ待っている
Still waiting for tomorrow's me.
わがままで のろまな 主の帰還を
For the return of the selfish, slow master.
どうせ幾年経って 車が空飛べど
Even if years pass and cars fly in the sky,
きっと幾年経って 機械が喋れども
even if years pass and machines can speak,
何だって言いたいんだ 便利という前に
I've got something to say: before calling it "convenience,"
心の傷口を 治してくれ
please heal the wounds in my heart.
あんな空でミサイルが飛ぶのなら
If missiles are to fly in a sky like that,
そんなもので幸せを呼ぶのなら
if happiness is to be called by such things,
優しい人になれなくちゃ 僕は僕を
then unless I can become a kind person,
肯定してゆけるかな
I wonder if I'll ever be able to affirm myself.
頭を上げて前向けと言われても
Even if told to lift my head and look forward,
暗闇じゃ前もクソもないな
in the darkness there's no "forward" or anything.
一人でいれど 二人でいれど
Whether I'm alone or with someone else,
この苦は孤独に変わりゃしねえ
this loneliness won't change into anything else.
死にたいなんて歌歌って
Singing songs about wanting to die,
またそれかと釘を打たれた
I was driven in like a nail with "That again?"
だけどそれほどのことしか
But there's only so much that
口からこぼれる言葉が どうしても
words spilling from my mouth can do, no matter what.
見つからないんだ
I just can't find them.
今日の僕もまたこうして
Today's me is again being
下賤に吸い込まれる 明日が...
sucked into the vulgarity like this. Tomorrow...
ハウツー世界征服
How-to World Domination
いければいいのにな
If only I could go
最終列車の汽笛がうるさくなり響く
The whistle of the last train echoes loudly
どうせ愛なんてって吐きこぼして強がっても きっと本心じゃ疚しさに襲われて
Even if I spit out "love is whatever" and act tough, I'm surely being attacked by guilt in my true feelings
期待現状の僕は そうかいどうしようもないな
I, with current expectations, well, there's nothing I can do
うるさいな お前なんて大嫌いだ
Shut up, I hate you!
あの空でミサイルが飛ぶのならば
If missiles were to fly in that sky
そんなもので命が飛ぶのならば
If lives were to fly because of such things
優しい人にならなくちゃ
I must become a kind person
僕も 僕も 肯定されたい
I, too, want to be affirmed
優しい人にならなくちゃ
I must become a kind person
心がかじかむ前に
Before my heart freezes
すいちゃん何だこれは！？
Suichan, what was that!?
声は！？
The voice!?
スリル！
Thrill!
ショック！
Shock!
サスペンス！
Suspense!
違うんですよ、この曲違うんですよ。
Wait, this isn't right. This isn't that song.
ハウツー世界征服です。
It's How-to World Domination.
そうなんですよ。
That's right.
でもリハでさ、
But in rehearsal,
リハですっごい一生懸命二人で、あのどんな感じにしようかって考えてた結果、
we were both thinking really hard about how to do it, and as a result,
もうどうしてもどうしても...
no matter what, no matter what...
もう何をどうしてもこうとしか鳴らなかったから、
no matter what we did, it just sounded like that,
じゃあもうこれでいこうって。
so we were like, "Let's just go with this."
これ入れなかったときボツだったもんね。
It was gonna be scrapped if we didn't put that in.
そう、もうこれにしたからね。
Yeah, so we went with this.
あ、これで誤魔化したんだ。
Ah, so you faked it with this.
あ、ふーたん。
Ah, Fu-tan.
誕生日らしいね。
I hear it's your birthday.
そうなんだよ！
That's right!
おめでとう！
Happy birthday!
ありがとう！
Thank you!
っていうか、すいちゃん忙しいのに、ね、ありがとう。
I mean, thanks for coming even though you're busy, Suichan.
だって二人で歌うのってそうそうないからね、実を言うと。
To be honest, we don't get many chances to sing as a duo.
そう、てか初めて...
Yeah, actually it's the first time...
なんか一緒に、誰かと一緒に歌う、みたいな。
like, singing together, just the two of us.
3人とか、しらけんとかはあったんだけど。
We've had trios or Shiraken, but...
ちょっとなんかすいちゃんと歌ってみたいなと思って。
I really wanted to try singing with Suichan.
歌うんだったらでも、あのすいちゃんのカッコいい低音と、私が得意な高音と、
But if we were going to sing, I wanted to hear Suichan's cool low notes mixed with my high notes,
なんか合わさったやつ聞いてみたくて。
I wanted to hear that combination.
あんますいちゃんってさ、そういうの歌ってないなと思って。
I felt like Suichan doesn't sing things like that very often.
高いの無理。
High notes are a no-go for me.
「これもアリだ」って思ってもらえたら嬉しいなと思って私もちょっと頑張ろうと思って。
I'd be happy if people thought "this is good too," so I decided to give it my all.
ハウツー世界征服めっちゃ合ってたと思う。
I think How-to World Domination suited us perfectly.
私もね、すいちゃんと歌えてめっちゃ嬉しかった。
I was really happy to sing with Suichan too.
あの「うるさいな お前なんて」がカッコいい！
That "Shut up, I hate you" part was so cool!
「大嫌いだ！」
I hate you!
でも私は好きだぞって思ってた。
But I was thinking, "I like you, though."
いや、頑張りました、あの高音、本当に。
Man, I really worked hard on those high notes.
もうそーたんが、もうスコーンって高音出すからさ、
Flare-tan's high notes are just so crisp,
すいちゃんは頑張ってもう、もう下の方を支えました。
so Suichan did her best to support the low end.
いやでも、支えてもらった低音がカッコよすぎて、
But the low notes you provided were way too cool,
めっちゃ好きって思って。
I really loved it.
ありがとう！
Thank you!
めっちゃ楽しかった！
It was so much fun!
ありがとう、また一緒に歌おう。
Thank you, let's sing together again.
ね、また一緒に歌いたい。
Yeah, I'd love to sing together again.
全力ジャンピング！
Zenkai Jumping!
Yeah, ah!!
全力ジャンピング！
Zenkai Jumping!
どこへ行こうか 計画なしで
Where shall we go? Without a plan
歌いながら気の向く方へ
Singing along, wherever we feel like
迷ってるの？ 冒険してるの？
Are you lost? Are you adventuring?
それは自分次第！
That's all up to you!
まだまだ楽しみ足んないっ
Not having enough fun yet!
足んない！
Not enough!
ワクワクすぐ明日へ
Excited for tomorrow already
思い切って 張り切って
Boldly, with all our might
前向いて さあ進もう
Facing forward, let's go!
せーのっ！
Ready, go!
One, two, go!
ハイ！
Hi!
どんときて 遊び尽くしちゃえ
Bring it on, let's play our hearts out
イッツ・オーライ！
It's Alright!
やりすぎちゃうくらいで イッツ・オーライ
It's okay to overdo it—it's alright!
ハイ！
Hi!
早起きも 徹夜しちゃお
Waking up early, staying up late
ハイ！
Hi!
なんとかなっちゃうはずだから
Because it'll all work out somehow
イッツ・オール・オッケー！
It's All Okay!
ピンチはチャンスになるからさ
A pinch will turn into a chance, you know
イッツ・オール・オッケー！
It's All Okay!
みんなで笑えば無敵だね
We're invincible when we laugh together
ハイ！
Hi!
なんたって全力で 突き抜けちゃって
Give it your all and break through
ハイ！
Hi!
まっすぐな気持ちで行こう
Let's go with straightforward feelings
ホップステップジャンピング！ 飛び出そう
Hop, step, jumping! Let's leap out
Yeah, ah!!
順調に行く時だけじゃ
If things only go smoothly
それはそれで退屈だね
then that's just boring, isn't it
わがままかもしれないけど
It might be selfish of me, but
失敗は成功の元！
Failure is the seed of success!
とか格好つけてみたけど
I tried to act all cool like that, but
やらかしちゃった日の夜は
on the nights I've really messed up
枕に向かって叫んだ
I screamed into my pillow
う～、せーの！
Ready... set, go!
今しかできない ことをしようよ
Let's do the things we can only do now!
ハイ！
Hai!
心配ご無用 無問題！
No need to worry, it's no problem!
走る前からつまずくことを
There's no point in thinking about tripping
ハイ！
Hai!
考えてちゃしょうがない
before you even start running!
もしも雨が降ったとしたら
If it happens to rain,
イッツ・オール・オッケー！
It's All Okay!
とっておきの傘をさそうよ
let's open our special umbrellas!
イッツ・オール・オッケー！
It's All Okay!
なんたって全力で突き抜けちゃって
Let's go all out and push through,
ハイ！
Hai!
まっすぐな気持ちで行こう
with straightforward feelings!
ホップステップジャンプで飛び出そう！
Let's fly out with a hop, step, and jump!
なかなかお布団から出られない日もある
There are days when you just can't get out of bed,
でも明日から そう明日から
but starting tomorrow, yes, starting tomorrow,
本気を出すんだ！
I'll give it my all!
日が沈むまで 日が暮れるまで
Until the sun sets, until the day ends,
門限なんか無視で イッツ・オーライ！
just ignore the curfew, it's alright!
早起きよりも 徹夜しちゃおう
Instead of waking up early, let's stay up all night!
ハイ！
Hai!
なんとかなっちゃうはずだから
Because everything should turn out fine!
ピンチはチャンスになるからさ
Since a pinch can turn into a chance,
イッツ・オール・オッケー！
It's All Okay!
みんなで笑えば無敵だね
we're invincible when we all laugh together!
イッツ・オール・オッケー！
It's All Okay!
なんたって全力で突き抜けちゃって
Let's go all out and push through,
ハイ！
Hai!
まっすぐな気持ちで行こう
with straightforward feelings!
ホップステップジャンプで飛び出そう！
Let's fly out with a hop, step, and jump!
Yeah!!
今日は会いに来てくれてありがとう
Thanks for coming to see me today.
不知火フレア誕生日記念グッズを紹介しちゃうよ
I'm going to introduce the Shiranui Flare
birthday commemorative goods!
lackパパの超キュートな描き下ろし、LEDアクリルスタンドライトや
An LED acrylic stand light with a super
cute illustration by lack-papa...
君たちエルフレンドのぬいぐるみ
...and a plushie of you Elfriends!
膝に乗せて、ぎゅって抱きしめられるほど良いサイズ
It's a size that's just right to keep
on your lap and give a big squeeze.
帽子や時計を自分好みにアレンジしてね
Arrange the hat and watch to your liking!
そして、おしゃれでシンプルで可愛いマルチポーチ
And, a stylish, simple, and cute multi-pouch.
私とお揃いで一緒に持たない？
Wanna have a matching one with me?
次に誕生日を記念して作っちゃったよ、ブレスレット
Next, I made this to commemorate my birthday:
a bracelet!
君の推しは私だぞってアピールしてくれるよね
You'll use it to show that I'm your oshi, right?
そんでもって、フルセットの購入特典
And then, the full set purchase bonus.
数量限定だけど、今年も直筆サイン書いちゃうぞ
It's limited quantity, but I'll be doing
handwritten signatures again this year!
さらにお知らせです！
Furthermore, an announcement!
私のLINEスタンプが発売されるってよ
My LINE stamps are going to be released!
イラストは佐々木先生が描いてくれたよ
The illustrations were drawn by Sasaki-sensei.
使いやすいスタンプがいっぱいだよ
There are lots of easy-to-use stamps.
恥ずかしいけど、二つだけ私が描いたイラストもあるよ
It's a bit embarrassing, but there are two
illustrations that I drew myself!
これで終わったと思うな！
Don't think it's over yet!
最後に歌った私の新曲
My new song that I sang at the end...
Massive New Krewさんと、篠崎あやとさんと、橘亮祐さんに作っていただいた
...produced by Massive New Krew, Ayato Shinozaki,
and Ryosuke Tachibana...
私の二作品目のオリジナルソング「全力ジャンピング！」が
...my second original song, 'Zenryoku Jumping!'...
このあと0時からリリースされるよ
...will be released at midnight tonight!
MVの公開は、もう少しだけ待っててね
Please wait a little longer for the MV release.
遅くなっちゃったけど、今年もたくさんみんなから
It's a bit late, but I'm so happy to receive
「おめでとう」って言ってもらえて幸せだー
so many 'happy birthday' messages
from everyone again this year.
みんな、いつも本当にありがとう
Everyone, thank you so much for everything.
愛してるぜー！
I love you!
（笑い）
(Laughs)